Rafat Anwar Munshi

Full Stack Developer Mumbai, India

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/rafatmunshi. GitHub: https://github.com/rafatmunshi

Contact No.: +91-7500602103. e-mail: munshi.rafat07@gmail.com

Profile Web Applications Developer with 5+ years of relevant experience developing Full Stack applications in the Technology, E-commerce and Education Industry. I focus on Business relevance and User experience by leveraging different technologies. I take pride in my Communication skills. I like when I am challenged, it brings me satisfaction to ace it.

Work Experience

Cisco Systems, India, IT Engineer

Business Applications Developer- July 2012- Nov 2014 (2 years 3 months)

Cisco Developer Network- www.developer.cisco.com (~ 1 year) Role: Individual Contributor (Team size- 8)

- Improved user experience by working closely with the team in the US to understand requirements, make Technical Design Document and develop quality code followed by unit testing.
- Developed enhancements on existing functionalities for the large-scale application.
- Built a Java API to upload videos to Cisco's video sharing platform using Quartz Scheduler. Made it available as a reusable component for 100s of Engineers to incorporate within any Cisco tool.
 Tech: Liferay, Spring portlet MVC

Delivery Collaboration Portal- www.dcp.cisco.com (~ 1 year) Role: Individual Contributor (Team size- 7)

- Actively contributed in a high performing team under the Agile process, to understand requirement stories, follow clean coding practice with test driven approach for the large-scale complex application.
- Created an interactive webpage which automated tasks in the application workflow thereby improving efficiency of Network Engineers and Task Managers using the system.
- Mentored 2 junior Developers which helped quickly overcome gaps in skills to start contributing to critical applications.

Tech: Java, Junit, Oracle DB, JQuery

Maroof Consultancy, UAE, Web Consultant

Web Consultant- Jan 2015- June 2016 (1 year 6 months)

Swag of India. Role: Core team member (Team size- 6)

- Involved in ecommerce website development and analytics for UAE and India based markets
- Established great user experience using Pixel Perfect UI Design and Internationalization
- Implemented API integrations and responsible for website traffic analytics report generation
- Lead project by taking product ownership. Implemented User testing to reduce post release issues
- Worked collaboratively, focusing on marketing, operations, and customer connection to keep up the product growth and customer satisfaction which increased website traffic and sales by 30%
 Tech: PHP WordPress- WooCommerce, Google Analytics, MailChimp

Aligarh Muslim University, India, Full Stack Applications Developer & Instructor

Technical Assistant (Computer) - Sept 2016 - Present (1 year 9 months relevant)

Internal Quality Assurance Cell (IQAC) Role: Project Lead (Team size- 4)

- Owned end-to-end deliverables individually of software applications from feature discussions, requirement gathering, release milestone planning to designing then coding, testing, debugging, documentation, deployment and maintenance.
- Suggested practical and scalable solutions after understanding the concerns of the Institute which improved efficiency of processes of a 15 persons team by more than 80%.
- Lead the project, working with all the stakeholders of the Institute for software adoption by 2000+ users, providing user interaction and support.
- Reduced number of requests to the Director, IQAC by 75% by becoming subject matter expert and first point of contact for report generation for the National Assessment and Accreditation Council (NAAC) using all the systems

Grievance Redressal System (~4 months)

Web system to track, notify and store time-bound grievances of various stakeholders of the university

Tech: Java, MySQL, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap

Students Feedback Portal (~6 months)

Web System for the university to gain and analyse feedback from students and faculty for their

subjects and departments.

Tech: Spring MVC, MongoDB, Google Charts API

Inventory Management System (~3 months)

Faculty Information Portal (~4 months) Centralised Web system to store details of faculty members, their subjects, classes and attendance. Tech: PHP, MySQL

Students Information Portal (~4 months) Web System for registration and storage of students' personal, admissions and fees detail with live status tracking.

Tech: Spring Boot, Hibernate, MySQL, ES6

Semi-automatic Web system that manages and stores information on inventory of the college. Tech: React.is

Other responsibilities (2 years 4 months)

- Taught Data Structures, Algorithms, Front End Development, Java Programming
- Guided students in their projects in Java, C++, Web development, Authentication
- Accomplished major improvements in Curriculum and Teaching methodologies
- Implemented Server administration to improve uptime and maintainability

Consultancies, Freelance, & Graduation Projects

- **Recursive Lambda, India, Software Engineer- (Nov 2020- Present)** Working on DevOps tasks. Tech: Python, Bash Scripting, GitLab CI/CD, Google Cloud Platform, Terraform, Docker
- Skill Lync, Online Course Instructor (July 2020 Present) Developing Full Stack Courses
- Supervised Speech Recognition- B.Tech project (2012)
 Machine Learning using Principal Component Analysis and Eigenvoice approach. Tech: MATLAB
- Website Development- Guardian Preschool, Mumbai. (2011). Tech: WordPress
- Website Development- Kamsarobar Forum NGO. (2010). Tech- ASP.NET

Other Achievements

- Publication- 'Evolutionary Algorithmic Approach for Data Mining', International Journal of Engineering Science and Technology (IJEST)- June 2017.
- Third rank in Mumbai, India in High School Certificate 2012.

Education

- Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech) 2012, CGPA- 8.5/10
 - Veermata Jijabai Technological Institute (V.J.T.I), Mumbai.
- Higher Secondary Education (H.S.C) 2008, Percentage- 94.5%

Skills

Java Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Liferay, JSP, Servlets, JDBC, JUnit

Frontend React.js (basic), HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript ES6, jQuery

Database MySQL, MongoDB, Oracle

Others RESTful Web Services, JSON, XML, PHP, WordPress, Algorithms, Data Structures

Version control Git, SVN Build Ant, Maven

DevOps (basics) Python, Bash Scripting, GitLab CI/CD, Google Cloud Platform, Terraform, Docker Certificates Oracle certified Java Associate (OCJA), Oracle certified Associate (OCA)- SQL Level 1

Knowledge of Systems Design, Design Patterns

I hereby affirm that the information furnished in this form is true and correct.

Place: Mumbai, India Rafat Anwar Munshi